

SIMPHIWE NDABA ACCOUNTANT | CODING MENTOR



SKILLS

Java | Python | SQL HTML | CSS | JavaScript Docker | Git

Debtors/Creditors/Cashbook Payroll Processing Evolution, Pastel, Accpac (300)

EDUCATION

HyperionDevSoftware

Engineering Bootcamp

University of Cape TownB.Com: Financial Accounting
2007 - 2010

George Campbell THS 2001-2005

CONTACT

0833387386

simmi.ndaba@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/simp hiwe-n-35075b140/

https://simminda.github.io/Si mphiwe_Ndaba_resume/

PROFILE

I have over 10 years accounts experience. My goal is to accept a challenging position in a dynamic environment where I can fully utilize my knowledge and skill-set + learn more. I am eager to be a part of a strong team where my calm systematic approach, attention to detail and effective communication skills will add real value

WORK EXPERIENCE

| General | l Accountar | ոt (Jun 23 - | - Current |
|------------------|----------------|--------------|-----------|
| Bofin Cor | nsulting (Acco | unting Serv | ices) |

☐ Implementing accounting systems for SMMEs
 ☐ Validation of source documents to General Ledger.
 ☐ Periodic reporting, Preparation and finalization of Trial Balance.
 ☐ Monitor and analyze financial discrepancies.
 ☐ Analytical Review of financial numbers and explanations.
 Technical Accountant (Today's Destiny Logistics (Emalahleni)
 ☐ Payroll reconciliations
 ☐ Debtors and Creditors Reconciliations.
 ☐ Processing of month-end Journals.
 ☐ Oversight to bank and cash flows.
 ☐ Month / Year-end Close Processes.
 ☐ Create and manage custom software solution for managing fleet

Freelance Software Engineering Mentor (Mar 22 – Current) (remote)
CoGrammar | HyperionDev (Edtech)

Reviewing student projects and provide mentorship in Java, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Machine Learning, Django..
 Conducting mentor calls and mock interviews.
 Designed fully functional Task manager in Python and pushed to Github
 Programmed fully functional Project Manager program with Java and mySQL
 Created an "avoid the obstacles" game with full visuals and audio
 Built Bond Calculator app with GUI using Python and Tkinter
 Co-developed and launched live website "www.lingode.com"

PERSONAL INFO Cargo, Office and Property Services (Facilities Maintenance + Logistics) **Date of Birth:** ☐ Financial Statements preparations 25 October 1987 ☐ Payroll processing **Gender:** ☐ Oversee Accounts payable & Accounts Receivable duties Male ☐ Reviewing and payment of all monthly statutory returns **Marital Status:** ☐ Full function Debtors and Creditors Single ☐ Cashbook maintenance **Identity number:** ☐ Financial Statements preparations 871025 5641 08 2 ☐ Reviewing and payment of all monthly statutory returns **Driver's License:** ☐ Posting to G/L and journals Code B ☐ Preparation of Management Accounts & Cashflow projections ☐ Maintaining the Asset Register ☐ Handling of queries in Finance Dept. ☐ Operations optimization analysis ☐ Liaising with auditors and business consultants **Credit Controller (JAN 2016 – FEB 2018) Accounting Information Cue Administration Solutions (PTY) LTD (Imports/Exports; Warehousing)** Systems **Debtors (Thrutainers International; Intermodal Cargo Solutions)** ☐ MS Office (Outlook, Word, Excel ☐ Daily Cash Allocations (incl. Pivot tables & VLOOKUP)) ☐ Sending out Statements and invoices ☐ **Sage Pastel** (used 2017-2020) ☐ Banking, maintenance and reconciliation of cheques and petty cash Intermediate level certification obtained 2015 ☐ Phoning of overdue accounts and maintenance of Debtors aging ☐ **Sage 300** (Accpac) (used 2016-2017) ☐ Assisting clients with daily queries ☐ **Freightware** (used 2012-2015; 2018); ☐ Compiling refund documentation and ensuring company procedure ☐ Parcel Perfect (used 2018) adhered to **■ Xero** (used 2023-24) **QuickBooks** (used 2011, 2023) ☐ Reconciliation of accounts and communicating findings to clients ☐ **Zoho Books** (used 2023) ☐ Monthly Close-off procedures ☐ **Sage One** (used 2021 2023) ☐ Open & Maintain Accounts in Company Library ☐ **Sage VIP** (used 2019-2020) ☐ Vendor Application completion Basic + Pro level certification ☐ Filing, Scanning, Archiving obtained ☐ Sage Pastel Payroll (used 2024) Cashbook (Thrutainers International; Intermodal Cargo Solutions; **Sage Evolution** (used 2021-2023) **Transworld Freight; Thrutainers Intercontinental)** ☐ **ShipShape** (used 2016-2017, 2022) ☐ Capturing Bank Statements ☐ Updating Daily Cash Flow Figures ☐ Loading payments for Suppliers/CODS/SARS ☐ Writing out cheques and dispensing petty cash **Professional Memberships** ☐ Filing of payment recons (Interests) Information Technology **Invoice Administrator (NOV 2012 – DEC 2015)** Software Engineering Bootcamp **Triton Express (PTY) LTD (Logistics)** Hyperion Development (2021) ☐ Ensuring correct client billing on system by checking waybills **UCT Forest Hill I.T. Committee** (2009)for correct capturing of all applicable charges. ☐ Investigating any discrepancies and then modifying the system and **Volunteer Work** verifying before generating invoices. World Mission Society (2014) ☐ Running Excel reports regularly to ensure clearance of waybills PACT – Passionate About Cape Town awaiting verification and bring problem to managements' attention. ☐ Query delivery and invoicing disputes with operations and clients. Music Glee Music & Drama Academy (2014) REFERENCES

Available on request

Accountant (Apr 2018 – Oct 2021)